Keira Hamilton

Oakland, CA | 858-220-9359 | keiramhamilton@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/keirahamilton

Professional Summary

I am a technical project manager proficient in Microsoft Office, Google Suite, and a range of project management software. I have eight years of experience in education, which allowed me to develop my communication, organization, and leadership skills.

Skills

- Written & verbal communication
- Organization
- Microsoft Office
- Google Suite
- Scrum

- Predictive methodologies
- Agile methodologies
- Jira
- Trello
- Asana

Education

Master's in Education | UC Berkeley | May 2017 | 4.0 GPA

Bachelor's in English Education | SFSU | May 2015 | Magna Cum Laude

Certificates

Agile with Atlassian Jira | Coursera | January 2021

 $\begin{array}{c} \textbf{Professional Scrum Master I} \mid Scrum.org \mid \\ December \ 2020 \end{array}$

Project Management Principles and Practices | Coursera | October 2020

Experience

Project Manager | Demystify Meditation Conference (Virtual), January 2021 - Present

- Utilized Asana to seamlessly organize and track project tasks.
- Increased team alignment and collaboration capabilities by spearheading the development of project documentation and organization systems.

Business Manager | Bushido Oakland (Oakland, CA), December 2020 - Present

- Developed a business plan to clearly outline company's goals and strategies.
- Created original branding and marketing content to promote services, including flyers, a website, and a blog.
- Organized scheduling, payments, and client communications using Google Suite.

Technical Project Management Program | Thinkful (Virtual), November 2020 - February 2021

- Used predictive and adaptive methodologies to meet project objectives.
- Carefully studied business cases to determine appropriate approaches and used Google Suite to produce necessary project documentation, including project charter, team charter, RACI,

- requirements traceability matrix, adaptive backlog, communications management plan, and stakeholder engagement matrix for a web development class project.
- Used Trello, Jira, and Google Suite to track project progress and produce status updates for stakeholders, including schedule and budget updates, EVM calculations, and a project management plan.

Department Lead | Leadership Public Schools (Richmond, CA), August 2019 - June 2020

- Increased vertical alignment and overall team member satisfaction within the department as measured by team-member feedback.
- Developed and successfully completed two long-term department-wide projects.
- Served as a member of the Instructional Leadership Team, participating in a data-driven approach to monitoring and supporting school wide initiatives.

English Teacher | Leadership Public Schools (Richmond, CA), August 2016 - June 2020

- Achieved Accomplished Teacher status in the 18-19 school year.
- Used adaptive methodologies to meet KPIs.
- Implemented a data-driven approach in order to meet desired learning outcomes, resulting in increased reading levels as measured by the MAP test.
- Performed gap analysis and implemented instructional changes, resulting in increased scores on standardized tests.
- Effectively resolved conflicts within a fast-paced environment.
- Developed original units and performance tasks, resulting in increased engagement and cultural relevance.
- Creatively utilized technology to support learning outcomes.

Lead Instructor | Camp Galileo (Oakland, CA), Summer 2016, 2018, 2019

- Implemented art curriculum designed to promote an innovator's mindset of being collaborative, visionary, determined, reflective, and courageous.
- Participated in activities meant to invoke the joy of camp including opening and closing ceremonies and all camp games.